export const data = [
    {
      question: "Which of the following sorting algorithms can be used to sort a random linked list with minimum time complexity?",
      option1: "Insertion Sort",
      option2: "Quick Sort",
      option3: "Heap Sort",
      option4: "Merge Sort",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "In the worst case, the number of comparisions needed to search a singly list of length n for a given element is ",
      option1: "log(2^n)",
      option2: "n/2",
      option3: "log(2^n)-1",
      option4: "n",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Let P be a singly linked list. Let Q be the the pointer to an intermediate node x in the list. What is the worst-case time complexity of the best known algorithm to delete the node Q from the list?",
      option1: "O(n)",
      option2: "O(log2 n)",
      option3: "O(logn)",
      option4: "O(1)",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the worst case time complexity of inserting n elements into an empty linked list, if the linked list needs to be maintained in sorted order ?",
      option1: "O(n)",
      option2: "O(n log n)",
      option3: "O(n^2)",
      option4: "O(1)",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is true about linked list implementation of stack?",
      option1: "In push operation, if new nodes are inserted at the beginning of linked list, then in pop operation, nodes must be removed from end",
      option2: "In push operation, if new nodes are inserted at the end, then in pop operation, nodes must be removed from the beginning",
      option3: "Both of the above",
      option4: "None of the above",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one of the following is an application of Stack Data Structure ?",
      option1: "Managing function calls",
      option2: "The stock span problem",
      option3: "Arithmetic expression evaluation",
      option4: "All of the above ",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What are the disadvantages of arrays ?",
      option1: "Index value of an array can be negative",
      option2: "Elements are sequentially accessed",
      option3: "Data structure like queue or stack cannot be implemented",
      option4: "There are chances of wastage of memory space if elements inserted in an array are lesser than the allocated size ",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: " Which data structure is used for implementing recursion?",
      option1: "Stack",
      option2: "Queue",
      option3: "List",
      option4: "Array",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required to check whether an expression contains a balanced parenthesis is?",
      option1: "Queue",
      option2: "Stack",
      option3: "Tree",
      option4: "Array",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "Which is the most appropriate data structure for reversing a word?",
      option1: "stack",
      option2: "queue",
      option3: "graph",
      option4: "tree",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: " Which data structure is based on the Last In First Out (LIFO) principle??",
      option1: "Tree",
      option2: "Linked List",
      option3: "Stack",
      option4: "Queue",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: " What is a data structure?",
      option1: "A programming language",
      option2: "A collection of algorithms",
      option3: "A way to store and organize data",
      option4: "A type of computer hardware",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: " Which data structure is used for implementing recursion?",
      option1: "Stack",
      option2: "Queue",
      option3: "List",
      option4: "Array",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: " Which of the following statement(s) about stack data structure is NOT correct?",
      option1: "Top of the Stack always contain the new node",
      option2: "Stack is the FIFO data structure",
      option3: "Null link is present in the last node at the bottom of the stack",
      option4: "Linked List are used for implementing Stacks",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: " Which of the following data structures can be used to implement queues?",
      option1: "Stack",
      option2: "Arrays",
      option3: "LinkedList",
      option4: "All the above",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: " Which of the following data structures allow insertion and deletion from both ends?",
      option1: "Stack",
      option2: "Deque",
      option3: "Queue",
      option4: "Strings",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: " Which of the following sorting algorithms provide the best time complexity in the worst-case scenario?",
      option1: "Merge Sort",
      option2: "Quick Sort",
      option3: "Bubble Sort",
      option4: "Selection Sort",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: " Which of the following is a Divide and Conquer algorithm?",
      option1: "Bubble Sort",
      option2: "Selection Sort",
      option3: "Heap Sort",
      option4: "Merge Sort",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: " What is the best case time complexity of the binary search algorithm?",
      option1: "O(1)",
      option2: "O(n)",
      option3: "O(log2n)",
      option4: "O(n^2)",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: " What is the time complexity to insert an element to the front of a LinkedList(head pointer given?",
      option1: "O(n)",
      option2: "O(1)",
      option3: "O(logn)",
      option4: "O(n^logn)",
      ans: 2,
    },
    


  ];